// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "What is the correct syntax to output ''Hello World'' in R?",
    answer: "All of the other answers are correct",
    options: [
      "'Hello World'",
      "All of the other answers are correct",
      "''Hello World''",
      "print(''Hello World'')"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "How do you insert COMMENTS in R code?",
    answer: "# This is a comment ",
    options: [
      "// This is a comment ",
      "# This is a comment ",
      "/* This is a comment",
      "/@ This is a comment"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "In R, you must declare the data type of a variable",
    answer: "False",
    options: [
      "False",
      "True",
      "Maybe",
      "I don't know"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "How do you create a variable named x with the numeric value 5?",
    answer: "x <- 5",
    options: [
      "x <- 5",
      "int x = 5",
      "x : 5",
      "x % 5"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which function is often used to concatenate elements?",
    answer: "paste()",
    options: [
      "concat()",
      "join()",
      "merge()",
      "paste()"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 6,
    question: "How can you assign the same value to multiple variables in one line?",
    answer: "var1 <- var2 <- var3 <- ''Orange''",
    options: [
      "var1 <- var2 <- var3 <- ''Orange''",
      "var1, var2, var3 <- ''Orange''",
      "var1, var2, var3 = ''Orange''",
      "var3, var1, var2 = ''Orange''"

    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 7,
    question: "The following values: 10.5, 55 and 787, belongs to which data type?",
    answer: "numeric",
    options: [
      "numeric",
      "Complex",
      "integer",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which operator can be used to compare two values?",
    answer: "==",
    options: [
      "><",
      "<>",
      "=",
      "=="
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 9,
    question: "What will the following function do with the str string: nchar(str) ?",
    answer: "Find the number of characters in the str string",
    options: [
      "Insert an escape character before the str string ",
      "Add a new line for each word inside the str string",
      "Add spaces to each word inside the str string",
      "Find the number of characters in the str string"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 10,
    question: "How do you create a function in R?",
    answer: "my_function <- function()",
    options: [
      "my_function <- function[]",
      "my_function <- function()",
      "my_function <- function.",
      "my_function <- function{}"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 11,
    question: "R is an alias of React.",
    answer: "False",
    options: [
      "True",
      "False",
      "Maybe",
      "I don't know"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Which operator is used to add together two values?",
    answer: "The + sign",
    options: [
      "The & sign",
      "The + sign",
      "The * sign",
      "The @ sign"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 13,
    question: "The value of a string variable can be surrounded by single quotes.",
    answer: "True",
    options: [
      "True",
      "False",
      "Maybe",
      "I don't know"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Which function can be used to return the square root of a number?",
    answer: "sqrt()",
    options: [
      "sqroot()",
      "sr()",
      "sqrt()",
      "square_root()"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "How do you call a function in R?",
    answer: "my_function()",
    options: [
      "(my_function);",
      "My_function[]",
      "My_function;",
      "my_function()"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Consider the following code: for (x 1:10). Which keyword is missing inside the for loop to output the numbers 1 to 10?",
    answer: "in",
    options: [
      "list",
      "in",
      "inside",
      "seq"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 17,
    question: "What is the correct way to create a vector of strings?",
    answer: "fruits <- c(''banana'', ''apple'', ''orange'')",
    options: [
      "fruits <- c(''banana'', ''apple'', ''orange'')",
      "fruits <- list(''banana'', ''apple'', ''orange'')",
      "fruits <- listOf(''banana'', ''apple'', ''orange'')",
      "fruits <- v(''banana'', ''apple'', ''orange'')"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 18,
    question: "What is the correct way to create a list of strings?",
    answer: "fruits <- list(''banana'', ''apple'', ''orange'')",
    options: [
      "fruits <- c(''banana'', ''apple'', ''orange'')",
      "fruits <- vectorOf(''banana'', ''apple'', ''orange'')",
      "fruits <- list(''banana'', ''apple'', ''orange'')",
      "fruits <- v(''banana'', ''apple'', ''orange'')"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which function can be used to create a data frame?",
    answer: "idata.frame()",
    options: [
      "df()",
      "dataframe()",
      "dframe()",
      "data.frame()"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Which function is used to draw points (markers) in a diagram?",
    answer: "plot(",
    options: [
      "d()",
      "canvas()",
      "draw()",
      "plot("
    ]
  },


  
  
  
  
  
  


  


 


  // you can uncomment the below codes and make duplicate as more as you want to add question
  // but remember you need to give the numb value serialize like 1,2,3,5,6,7,8,9.....

  //   {
  //   numb: 6,
  //   question: "Your Question is Here",
  //   answer: "Correct answer of the question is here",
  //   options: [
  //     "Option 1",
  //     "option 2",
  //     "option 3",
  //     "option 4"
  //   ]
  // },
];